A Guide to the Papers of Edward L. Schrock, 1999-2004
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
Papers of Edward L. Schrock 1999-2004
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
82
34 Hollinger Document Cases, 25 Preservation Binders, and 5 Card Boxes. 24 linear feet
Schrock, Edward L.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Open to researchers without restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift from Edward L. Schrock, December 2004.
Biographical/Historical Information
Republican Edward Lee Schrock (born April 6, 1941) served on the U.S. House of Representatives for the 2nd Congressional District of Virginia from January 2001 to January 2005. Schrock was preceded by Owen Pickett, and succeeded by Thelma Drake in this position.
The 2nd Congressional District includes Virginia's Eastern Shore, Virginia Beach, and parts of Norfolk and Hampton. The district tends to be conservative housing eight military installations and Pat Robertson's Christian Broadcasting Network.
Schrock was born in Middleton, Ohio. He attended Alderson-Broaddus College and the American University where he earned a Master's Degree in Public Relations. He served in the U.S. Navy from 1964 to 1988, including two tours of duty in Vietnam. Later he served as director of public affairs at the headquarters of the NATO Supreme Allied Commander in Norfolk, and retired from the Navy in 1988 with the rank of captain. After the Navy, Schrock worked as an investment broker six years with a national brokerage and investment firm. He then ran two successful campaigns for the Virginia Senate, where he represented the 7th senatorial district from 1995 to 2001. There he earned a reputation for his reliable conservative voting record. Schrock belongs to the Atlantic Shores Baptist Church, is married to Judith Adnee Crawford, and has one child, a son named Randy.
During his time in Congress Schrock served on the House Armed Services Committee, House Budget Committee, House Small Business Committee, and House Reforms Committee. In 2003 Schrock was chosen to serve as the Chairman of the Regulatory Reform and Oversight Committee of the House Committee on Small Business. He founded and co-chaired the House Navy / Marine Corps Caucus and the House Special Operations Forces Caucus. Schrock's political and voting record is aligned closely with the Republican Party. Schrock favors fewer restrictions on gun ownership, strong restrictions on abortion, and increased military spending. Other issues important to Schrock are defense issues related to shipbuilding and personnel. The Christian Coalition gave him a 92% rating in their 2003 voting guide and the National Journal rated him as the second most conservative person in all of Congress for the same year.
Among his other accomplishments and concerns, Schrock has also been a longtime advocate of public libraries. He was appointed by Virginia Governor George Allen to serve on the Library Board of Virginia. He served on the Library of Virginia Foundation Board; for ten years he served as President of the Friends of the Virginia Beach Public Library. He also served in a leadership role in Hampton Roads events such as Harborfest, the International Azalea Festival, and Tradefest. A cancer survivor, he served on the board of directors of Lee's Friends, a cancer victims support group. He served as a president of the Parent / Faculty Association at Cape Henry Collegiate School. From 1985 onward, Schrock has been involved with over 19 charitable and service organizations in Hampton Roads.
On August 30, 2004 Schrock dropped out of his race for a third term in Congress due to allegations that he had made use of a gay telephone service to meet other men and that he was secretly gay or at least bisexual. The website Blog Active, a gay political website that frequently "outs" closeted gay and allegedly gay politicians who support anti-gay legislation, even posted voice recordings that they said was Schrock using the gay phone service to solicit sex from other men. During his time in office, Schrock opposed various gay rights issues including same-sex marriage and gays in the military, and he co-sponsored the Federal Marriage Amendment.
Scope and Content
The papers of Edward L. Schrock date from 1999 to 2004. A large portion of the collection is composed of constituent feedback in the form of letters, postcards, petitions, surveys, and opinion ballots. Also included are a small number of letters from Schrock to constituents and correspondence with colleagues, committee business for the U.S. House of Representatives Committee on Small Business, and reference material related to various issues and legislation.
Index Terms
Schrock, Edward L.; Legislators--Virginia; United States. Congress. House
Contents List
- Correspondence 1999-2004
  This series is divided into six sub-series of correspondence to or from Representative Schrock and constituents or colleagues. Materials include letters, petitions, postcards, and e-mail.
  - Letters from Constituents 1999-2004
    This sub-series contains letters from constituents to Ed Schrock during his term in the U.S. House of Representatives, as well as a small number of letters preceding his term. Letters date from 1999 to 2004. Topics include, but are not limited to: the 9-11 attacks, abortion, AIDS and HIV, animal rights, capital punishment, campaign finance reform, cloning, energy, the economy, the environment, the Faith Based Initiative and Charitable Choice, flag desecration, gay rights, gun control, hate crimes, health care, higher education, Homeland Security, illegal immigrants, illegal drugs, interstate waste, Iraq, Israel, Medicare and Medicaid, military and veteran benefits, Napster and file sharing, pension reform, privacy rights, public schools, school prayer, small business, social security, stem cell research, taxes, terrorism, the United Nations, welfare reform, and many other topics.
    Chronological by year and then alphabetical within each year
    - Various January 1999 (Box-folder 1:1)
    - Various January 2000 (Box-folder 1:2)
    - Various November 2000 (Box-folder 1:3)
    - Various December 2000 (Box-folder 1:4)
    - Various 2000 (Box-folder 1:5)
    - Abortion January 2001 (Box-folder 1:6)
    - Animal Rights January 2001 (Box-folder 1:7)
    - Ashcroft, John, Nomination for Attorney General January 2001 (Box-folder 1:8)
    - Bush Administration January 2001 (Box-folder 1:9)
    - Capital Punishment / Death Penalty January 2001 (Box-folder 1:10)
    - Clean Energy January 2001 (Box-folder 1:11)
    - Cloning January 2001 (Box-folder 1:12)
    - Concurrent Receipt of Military and Retired Pay and VA Disability Compensation January 2001 (Box-folder 1:13)
    - Environment January 2001 (Box-folder 1:14)
    - Equity in Prescription Insurance and Contraceptive Coverage Act (EPICC) January 2001 (Box-folder 1:15)
    - Faith Based Initiative / Charitable Choice January 2001 (Box-folder 1:16)
    - FDA Patient Rights Act January 2001 (Box-folder 1:17)
    - Ferrell Parkway January 2001 (Box-folder 1:18)
    - Flag Desecration January 2001 (Box-folder 1:19)
    - Fort Story Golf Course January 2001 (Box-folder 1:20)
    - Graduate Medical Education in Independent Children's Teaching Hospitals January 2001 (Box-folder 1:21)
    - Gun Control January 2001 (Box-folder 1:22)
    - Hate Crimes January 2001 (Box-folder 1:23)
    - HUD / FHA Real Estate Appraisers January 2001 (Box-folder 1:24)
    - Illegal Immigrants January 2001 (Box-folder 1:25)
    - Interstate Waste January 2001 (Box-folder 1:26)
    - Juvenile Crime January 2001 (Box-folder 1:27)
    - Medicare January 2001 (Box-folder 1:28)
    - Military / Veteran's Benefits January 2001 (Box-folder 1:29)
    - Privacy Rights January 2001 (Box-folder 1:30)
    - School Prayer January 2001 (Box-folder 1:31)
    - Sex Education January 2001 (Box-folder 1:32)
    - Social Security January 2001 (Box-folder 1:33)
    - Stem Cell Research January 2001 (Box-folder 1:34)
    - Taxes January 2001 (Box-folder 1:35)
    - Various January 2001 (Box-folder 1:36)
    - Abortion February 2001 (Box-folder 1:37)
    - Arctic National Wildlife Refuge February 2001 (Box-folder 1:38)
    - Bush Administration February 2001 (Box-folder 1:39)
    - Capital Punishment / Death Penalty February 2001 (Box-folder 1:40)
    - Children's Issues February 2001 (Box-folder 1:41)
    - Clean Diamonds Act February 2001 (Box-folder 1:42)
    - Clinton, Bill, Office Space February 2001 (Box-folder 1:43)
    - Concurrent Receipt of Military and Retired Pay and VA Disability Compensation February 2001 (Box-folder 1:44)
    - Email Tax February 2001 (Box-folder 1:45)
    - Environment February 2001 (Box-folder 1:46)
    - Faith Based Initiative / Charitable Choice February 2001 (Box-folder 1:47)
    - FDA Patient Rights Act February 2001 (Box-folder 1:48)
    - Fort Story Golf Course February 2001 (Box-folder 1:49)
    - Gay Rights February 2001 (Box-folder 2:1)
    - Gun Control February 2001 (Box-folder 2:2)
    - Health Care February 2001 (Box-folder 2:3)
    - Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA) February 2001 (Box-folder 2:4)
    - Interstate Waste February 2001 (Box-folder 2:5)
    - Israel February 2001 (Box-folder 2:6)
    - Medicare February 2001 (Box-folder 2:7)
    - Military / Veteran's Benefits February 2001 (Box-folder 2:8)
    - Napster / File Sharing I February 2001 (Box-folder 2:9)
    - Napster / File Sharing II February 2001 (Box-folder 2:10)
    - Napster / File Sharing III February 2001 (Box-folder 2:11)
    - Napster / File Sharing IV February 2001 (Box-folder 2:12)
    - Privacy Rights February 2001 (Box-folder 2:13)
    - Railroad Retirement Reform February 2001 (Box-folder 2:14)
    - Realty Regulations I February 2001 (Box-folder 2:15)
    - Realty Regulations II February 2001 (Box-folder 2:16)
    - Realty Regulations III February 2001 (Box-folder 2:17)
    - School Prayer February 2001 (Box-folder 2:18)
    - Service Corps of Retired Executives (SCORE) February 2001 (Box-folder 2:19)
    - Schrock, Ed -- Election to Office February 2001 (Box-folder 2:20)
    - Schrock, Ed -- Office Location February 2001 (Box-folder 2:21)
    - Stem Cell Research February 2001 (Box-folder 2:22)
    - Taxes February 2001 (Box-folder 3:1)
    - Tricare Coverage for Military Retirees February 2001 (Box-folder 3:2)
    - United Nations February 2001 (Box-folder 3:3)
    - Various February 2001 (Box-folder 3:4)
    - Abortion March 2001 (Box-folder 3:5)
    - Airlines March 2001 (Box-folder 3:6)
    - Arctic National Wildlife Refuge March 2001 (Box-folder 3:7)
    - Boy Scouts March 2001 (Box-folder 3:8)
    - Campaign Finance Reform March 2001 (Box-folder 3:9)
    - Clean Diamonds Act March 2001 (Box-folder 3:10)
    - Concurrent Receipt of Military and Retired Pay and VA Disability Compensation I March 2001 (Box-folder 3:11)
    - Concurrent Receipt of Military and Retired Pay and VA Disability Compensation II March 2001 (Box-folder 3:12)
    - Concurrent Receipt of Military and Retired Pay and VA Disability Compensation III March 2001 (Box-folder 3:13)
    - Concurrent Receipt of Military and Retired Pay and VA Disability Compensation IV March 2001 (Box-folder 3:14)
    - Concurrent Receipt of Military and Retired Pay and VA Disability Compensation V March 2001 (Box-folder 3:15)
    - Email Tax March 2001 (Box-folder 3:16)
    - Environment March 2001 (Box-folder 3:17)
    - Ergonomics March 2001 (Box-folder 3:18)
    - Faith Based Initiative / Charitable Choice March 2001 (Box-folder 4:1)
    - Ferrell Parkway March 2001 (Box-folder 4:2)
    - Fort Story Golf Course March 2001 (Box-folder 4:3)
    - Gun Control March 2001 (Box-folder 4:4)
    - Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (IDEA) March 2001 (Box-folder 4:5)
    - Internet Freedom and Broadband Deployment Act March 2001 (Box-folder 4:6)
    - Israel March 2001 (Box-folder 4:7)
    - Life Insurance March 2001 (Box-folder 4:8)
    - Medical Privacy March 2001 (Box-folder 4:9)
    - Medicare March 2001 (Box-folder 4:10)
    - Military / Veteran's Benefits March 2001 (Box-folder 4:11)
    - Napster / File Sharing March 2001 (Box-folder 4:12)
    - National Defense Authorization Act March 2001 (Box-folder 4:13)
    - Public Schools March 2001 (Box-folder 4:14)
    - Railroad Retirement Reform March 2001 (Box-folder 4:15)
    - Social Security March 2001 (Box-folder 4:16)
    - Taxes March 2001 (Box-folder 4:17)
    - Telecommunications Act of 1996 March 2001 (Box-folder 4:18)
    - Tricare March 2001 (Box-folder 4:19)
    - Various March 2001 (Box-folder 4:20)
    - Africa April 2001 (Box-folder 4:21)
    - Africa, Hunger In April 2001 (Box-folder 4:22)
    - Airline Labor Disputes April 2001 (Box-folder 4:23)
    - Anesthesia Safety Act April 2001 (Box-folder 4:24)
    - Arctic National Wildlife Refuge April 2001 (Box-folder 4:25)
    - Campaign Finance Reform April 2001 (Box-folder 4:26)
    - Capital Punishment / Death Penalty April 2001 (Box-folder 4:27)
    - China April 2001 (Box-folder 4:28)
    - Concurrent Receipt of Military and Retired Pay and VA Disability Compensation April 2001 (Box-folder 4:29)
    - Diabetes April 2001 (Box-folder 4:30)
    - Environment April 2001 (Box-folder 5:1)
    - Equal Protection of Voting Rights Act April 2001 (Box-folder 5:2)
    - Faith Based Initiative / Charitable Choice April 2001 (Box-folder 5:3)
    - FDA Patient Rights Act April 2001 (Box-folder 5:4)
    - Gay Rights April 2001 (Box-folder 5:5)
    - Gun Control April 2001 (Box-folder 5:6)
    - Hate Crimes April 2001 (Box-folder 5:7)
    - Health Care Benefits for those Participating in Recreation Activities April 2001 (Box-folder 5:8)
    - Health Issues April 2001 (Box-folder 5:9)
    - Keep Our Promise to America's Retiree's Act April 2001 (Box-folder 5:10)
    - Life Insurance April 2001 (Box-folder 5:11)
    - Medical Privacy April 2001 (Box-folder 5:12)
    - Medicare April 2001 (Box-folder 5:13)
    - Military / Veteran's Benefits April 2001 (Box-folder 5:14)
    - Napster / File Sharing April 2001 (Box-folder 5:15)
    - NASA: Pluto-Kuiper Express Mission April 2001 (Box-folder 5:16)
    - Pension Reform April 2001 (Box-folder 5:17)
    - Privacy Rights April 2001 (Box-folder 5:18)
    - Public Schools April 2001 (Box-folder 5:19)
    - Railroad Retirement Reform April 2001 (Box-folder 5:20)
    - Secret Evidence Repeal Act April 2001 (Box-folder 5:21)
    - Slave Reparations April 2001 (Box-folder 5:22)
    - Social Security April 2001 (Box-folder 5:23)
    - Stem Cell Research April 2001 (Box-folder 5:24)
    - Taxes April 2001 (Box-folder 5:25)
    - Telecommunications Act of 1996 April 2001 (Box-folder 5:26)
    - Toxic Chemicals April 2001 (Box-folder 5:27)
    - Urban Sprawl April 2001 (Box-folder 5:28)
    - Washington Hospital Center April 2001 (Box-folder 5:29)
    - Various April 2001 (Box-folder 5:30)
    - Abortion May 2001 (Box-folder 5:31)
    - Africa, Hunger In May 2001 (Box-folder 5:32)
    - Airline Pilots May 2001 (Box-folder 5:33)
    - Anesthesia Safety Act May 2001 (Box-folder 5:34)
    - Animal Rights May 2001 (Box-folder 5:35)
    - Arctic National Wildlife Refuge May 2001 (Box-folder 5:36)
    - Boy Scouts May 2001 (Box-folder 5:37)
    - Campaign Finance Reform May 2001 (Box-folder 5:38)
    - Clean Energy May 2001 (Box-folder 5:39)
    - Concurrent Receipt of Military and Retired Pay and VA Disability Compensation May 2001 (Box-folder 5:40)
    - Drugs May 2001 (Box-folder 6:1)
    - Education Bill May 2001 (Box-folder 6:2)
    - Enumerated Powers Act May 2001 (Box-folder 6:3)
    - Environment May 2001 (Box-folder 6:4)
    - Faith Based Initiative / Charitable Choice May 2001 (Box-folder 6:5)
    - Ferrell Parkway May 2001 (Box-folder 6:6)
    - Flag Desecration May 2001 (Box-folder 6:7)
    - Gun Control May 2001 (Box-folder 6:8)
    - Global Gag Rule May 2001 (Box-folder 6:9)
    - Head Start Program May 2001 (Box-folder 6:10)
    - Health Issues May 2001 (Box-folder 6:11)
    - Higher Education Act May 2001 (Box-folder 6:12)
    - Hope for Children Act May 2001 (Box-folder 6:13)
    - Humanitarian Exports Leading to Peace Act May 2001 (Box-folder 6:14)
    - Inexpensive Book Distribution Program May 2001 (Box-folder 6:15)
    - Military / Veteran's Benefits May 2001 (Box-folder 6:16)
    - Napster / File Sharing May 2001 (Box-folder 6:17)
    - Pension Reform May 2001 (Box-folder 6:18)
    - Privacy Rights May 2001 (Box-folder 6:19)
    - Public Schools May 2001 (Box-folder 6:20)
    - Realty Regulations May 2001 (Box-folder 6:21)
    - Small Business Pollution Prevention Opportunity Act May 2001 (Box-folder 6:22)
    - Stem Cell Research May 2001 (Box-folder 6:23)
    - Taxes May 2001 (Box-folder 6:24)
    - Telecommunications Act of 1996 May 2001 (Box-folder 6:25)
    - Tricare May 2001 (Box-folder 6:26)
    - United Nations May 2001 (Box-folder 6:27)
    - World War II Memorial May 2001 (Box-folder 6:28)
    - Various May 2001 (Box-folder 6:29)
    - Abortion June 2001 (Box-folder 6:30)
    - AIDS / HIV June 2001 (Box-folder 6:31)
    - Arctic National Wildlife Refuge June 2001 (Box-folder 6:32)
    - Back Bay Wildlife Refuge June 2001 (Box-folder 6:33)
    - Bipartisan Patient Protection Act June 2001 (Box-folder 6:34)
    - Boy Scouts June 2001 (Box-folder 6:35)
    - Campaign Finance Reform June 2001 (Box-folder 6:36)
    - Clean Diamonds Act June 2001 (Box-folder 6:37)
    - Clean Energy June 2001 (Box-folder 6:38)
    - Concurrent Receipt of Military and Retired Pay and VA Disability Compensation June 2001 (Box-folder 6:39)
    - Employment Non-Discrimination Act (ENDA) June 2001 (Box-folder 6:40)
    - Environment June 2001 (Box-folder 6:41)
    - Equity in Prescription Insurance and Contraceptive Coverage Act (EPICC) June 2001 (Box-folder 6:42)
    - Equity in Prescription Insurance and Contraceptive Coverage Act (EPICC) June 2001 (Box-folder 6:43)
    - Faith Based Initiative / Charitable Choice June 2001 (Box-folder 6:44)
    - Flag Desecration June 2001 (Box-folder 6:45)
    - Forced Choice between VA / DoD Health Care June 2001 (Box-folder 6:46)
    - Gallardo, Jose June 2001 (Box-folder 7:1)
    - Genetic Nondiscrimination in Health Insurance and Employment Act June 2001 (Box-folder 7:2)
    - Global Gag Rule June 2001 (Box-folder 7:3)
    - Global Health Act June 2001 (Box-folder 7:4)
    - Gun Control June 2001 (Box-folder 7:5)
    - Hate Crimes June 2001 (Box-folder 7:6)
    - Inexpensive Book Distribution Program June 2001 (Box-folder 7:7)
    - Internet Freedom and Broadband Deployment Act June 2001 (Box-folder 7:8)
    - Israel June 2001 (Box-folder 7:9)
    - Kadeer, Rebiya June 2001 (Box-folder 7:10)
    - Medicare June 2001 (Box-folder 7:11)
    - Military / Veteran's Benefits June 2001 (Box-folder 7:12)
    - Missiles June 2001 (Box-folder 7:13)
    - Napster / File Sharing June 2001 (Box-folder 7:14)
    - National Monument Fairness Act June 2001 (Box-folder 7:15)
    - Privacy Rights June 2001 (Box-folder 7:16)
    - Public Schools June 2001 (Box-folder 7:17)
    - Puerto Rico June 2001 (Box-folder 7:18)
    - Racial Profiling June 2001 (Box-folder 7:19)
    - Realty Regulations June 2001 (Box-folder 7:20)
    - Stem Cell Research June 2001 (Box-folder 7:21)
    - Social Security June 2001 (Box-folder 7:22)
    - Survivor Benefit Plan (SBP) June 2001 (Box-folder 7:23)
    - Taxes June 2001 (Box-folder 7:24)
    - Tax Competition June 2001 (Box-folder 7:25)
    - Telecommunications Act of 1996 June 2001 (Box-folder 7:26)
    - Truthfulness, Responsibility, and Accountability in Contracting Act (TRAC)) June 2001 (Box-folder 7:27)
    - UFO's and Extraterrestrials June 2001 (Box-folder 7:28)
    - Virginia Budget June 2001 (Box-folder 7:29)
    - Working Lands Stewardship Act June 2001 (Box-folder 7:30)
    - Various June 2001 (Box-folder 7:31)
    - Abortion July 2001 (Box-folder 7:32)
    - AIDS, HIV, and STD's July 2001 (Box-folder 7:33)
    - American Sovereignty Restoration Act July 2001 (Box-folder 7:34)
    - Arctic National Wildlife Refuge July 2001 (Box-folder 7:35)
    - Base Closings July 2001 (Box-folder 7:36)
    - Beaches Environmental Health Assessment and Coastal Health (BEACH) Act July 2001 (Box-folder 7:37)
    - Birth Control / Family Planning July 2001 (Box-folder 7:38)
    - Boy Scouts July 2001 (Box-folder 7:39)
    - Campaign Finance Reform July 2001 (Box-folder 7:40)
    - Clean Energy July 2001 (Box-folder 7:41)
    - Cloning July 2001 (Box-folder 7:42)
    - Concurrent Receipt of Military and Retired Pay and VA Disability Compensation July 2001 (Box-folder 7:43)
    - Elections / Voting July 2001 (Box-folder 8:1)
    - Email Tax July 2001 (Box-folder 8:2)
    - Employment Non-Discrimination Act (ENDA) July 2001 (Box-folder 8:3)
    - Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) July 2001 (Box-folder 8:4)
    - Faith Based Initiative / Charitable Choice July 2001 (Box-folder 8:5)
    - Federal Employees Health Benefits Program (FEHBP) Premiums July 2001 (Box-folder 8:6)
    - Federal Prison Industries Competition in Contracting Act July 2001 (Box-folder 8:7)
    - Flag Desecration July 2001 (Box-folder 8:8)
    - Genetically Engineered Fish July 2001 (Box-folder 8:9)
    - Gifted and Talented Students Act July 2001 (Box-folder 8:10)
    - Glacier Bay National Park and Preserve, Alaska July 2001 (Box-folder 8:11)
    - Gun Control July 2001 (Box-folder 8:12)
    - Health Care Finance Association Regulations (Recreational Activities) July 2001 (Box-folder 8:13)
    - Illegal Aliens July 2001 (Box-folder 8:14)
    - Innocence Protection Act July 2001 (Box-folder 8:15)
    - Iran / Libya July 2001 (Box-folder 8:16)
    - Israel July 2001 (Box-folder 8:17)
    - Jet Noise July 2001 (Box-folder 8:18)
    - Keep Our Promise to America's Military Retirees Act July 2001 (Box-folder 8:19)
    - Land Grab Bill July 2001 (Box-folder 8:20)
    - Low Frequency Active (LFA) Sonar July 2001 (Box-folder 8:21)
    - Medicare July 2001 (Box-folder 8:22)
    - Medicare Dialysis Benefit Improvement Act July 2001 (Box-folder 8:23)
    - Military / Veteran's Benefits July 2001 (Box-folder 8:24)
    - Missiles July 2001 (Box-folder 8:25)
    - Napster / File Sharing July 2001 (Box-folder 8:26)
    - Penny Use July 2001 (Box-folder 8:27)
    - Pension Reform July 2001 (Box-folder 8:28)
    - Public Schools July 2001 (Box-folder 8:29)
    - Realty Regulations July 2001 (Box-folder 8:30)
    - Retired Pay Restoration Act July 2001 (Box-folder 8:31)
    - Roadless Area Conservation Rule July 2001 (Box-folder 8:32)
    - Salmon Planning Act July 2001 (Box-folder 8:33)
    - Social Security July 2001 (Box-folder 8:34)
    - Stem Cell Research July 2001 (Box-folder 8:35)
    - Taxes July 2001 (Box-folder 8:36)
    - Telecommunications Act of 1996 July 2001 (Box-folder 8:37)
    - Title 9 July 2001 (Box-folder 8:38)
    - Truthfulness, Responsibility, and Accountability in Contracting Act (TRAC) July 2001 (Box-folder 8:39)
    - UFO's and Extraterrestrials July 2001 (Box-folder 8:40)
    - United Nations July 2001 (Box-folder 8:41)
    - Virginia Budget July 2001 (Box-folder 8:42)
    - Windfall Elimination Provision July 2001 (Box-folder 8:43)
    - Working Lands Stewardship Act July 2001 (Box-folder 8:44)
    - Various July 2001 (Box-folder 8:45)
    - Abortion August 2001 (Box-folder 8:46)
    - American Sovereignty Restoration Act August 2001 (Box-folder 8:47)
    - Arctic National Wildlife Refuge August 2001 (Box-folder 8:48)
    - Breast Cancer Research Stamp August 2001 (Box-folder 8:49)
    - Campaign Finance Reform August 2001 (Box-folder 8:50)